MAQSOOD AHMED ANSARI

Data Analytics Trainee with Expertise in Python, SQL, Power BI, and Data Analysis

\ +91 9030901068

@ magsood.a.ansari@gmail.com

Hyderabad, IN

SUMMARY

Energetic Data Science professional with a year's experience, specializing in Data Analytics, Machine Learning, and Al. Committed to using my skills and passion for data to drive measurable results and make a significant impact in the industry.

EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Trainee

Trainity

07/2023 - 09/2023

Remote IN

Data Science and Machine Learning Intern

Gilbert Research Center

m 05/2023 - 07/2023

Ocimbatore, IN

Data Analysis Industry Training

Brainnest

= 01/2023 - 02/2023

Remote, Berlin

PROJECTS

Instagram User Analytics

₯ https://github.com/MacAns-117/Projects/tree/main/Instagram_User_Analytics

Performed comprehensive analysis of Instagram data for marketing and investor metrics using SQL queries and MySQL Workbench. Formulated data-driven recommendations based on query results.

Play Store Apps Analysis & Visualization using SQL & Power BI

https://github.com/MacAns-

117/Projects/tree/main/Playstore %20 Apps %20 Analysis %20%26%20 Visualization

Collected, cleaned, processed, and transformed Play store data using Python, SQL, Power BI, and MS Excel. Presented findings using data visualization tools.

Hotel Churn Rate

https://github.com/MacAns-117/Projects/tree/main/Hotel_churn_rate

Enabled accurate forecasting of hotel booking cancellations by customers through robust data analysis using libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, and Missingno.

Cricket Data Performance Dashboard

https://github.com/MacAns-117/Projects/tree/main/Cricket_Data_Performance_Dashboard

Extracted cricket data from ESPN Cricinfo using web scraping techniques. Created an insightful dashboard for data visualization using Power BI.

House Price Prediction Using Advanced Regression **Techniques**

https://github.com/MacAns-

117/Projects/tree/main/Predicting_HP_Using_ADV_Ensamble_Techniques

Conducted a comprehensive price prediction analysis for Indian houses using advanced libraries and machine learning techniques, gaining a deep understanding of the Indian housing market.

Stella Bot

https://github.com/MacAns-117/Projects/tree/main/Stella_Bot

Developed a voice-interactive virtual assistant, Stella Bot, demonstrating proficiency in Python programming and predefined rule sets.

EDUCATION

M Tech, CSE

Osmania University

SKILLS

Python SQL **MS Excel Power Bi**

Data Cleaning Data Analysis

Data Visualization Data Analytics

Machine Learning Deep Learning

TensorFlow IBM SPSS Statistics

Tableau

CERTIFICATION

Accenture Data Analytics and Visualization Virtual Experience

Forage

PwC Power Bi Virtual Experience Program

Forage

IBM Data Science

Coursera

TensorFlow Developer Certificate

TensorFlow

AWS Certified Machine Learning Specialty

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS

ONLINE PRESENCE

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/username

GitHub

MacAns-117 (Magsood Ahmed Ansari) · GitHub



Portfolio

macans-117.github.io/Portfolio/

LANGUAGES

English

Proficient



Hindi

Advanced